Fernando Tinoco



fernandotinoco_45@hotmail.com



(505) 8994-7284





^{ADDRESS} Managua, Nicaragua



PHONE

(505) 2227-7060



EMAIL

ftinococ.45@gmail.com



weвsiте www.linkedin.com/in/ftino coc45

Summary

Software engineer specialized in web development, with around 5 years experience in this field. Tech enthusiast, passion to learn something new every day, and always with the desire to face new challenges that take me to a new level.

Language

- · English Middle
- Spanish Native

Experiences

→ 2019

Development Engineer Consultant

Consulting Group - Managua, Nicaragua (Remote)



Development of modules for academic staff management and homework management (student and teacher administration) and intercommunication with business services (C#, .NET Core, SQL Server, Oracle, Azure DevOps)

Development of profitability data processing application for Central American Bank for Economic Integration, development of setting forms, also implementation and development of calculation processes cost effectiveness (C#, ASP.NET MVC 5, DevExtreme, Oracle, Azure DevOps)

\rightarrow 2016 - 2019

Software Developer

Xolo S.A - Managua, Nicaragua



Collaboration in the development of an export module, port management and statistics, ETL implementation for Data Warehouse management in an Integrated Export and Import System for VUCEN (Nicaraguan Single Window for Foreign Trade) (JEE, Primefaces UI Framework, Oracle, Maven, GIT, SVN, Oracle, Glassfish).

Develop of a Digital Documentation Application for Telefónica Nicaragua (Java 8, Maven, Angular 8, Oracle, NodeJS, Git).

Develop of a Information Management System in quarentine module for IPSA (Institute for Agricultural Protection and Health) (C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET MVC 5, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Visual SourceSafe).

Collaboration in development of Appraisal System module. (C#, ASP.NET, SQL Server , Transact SQL).

Collaboration in the development of the sales cancellation module(Java, ZK Web Framework).

Migration of the Production Control System from Ruby to Java (PrimeFaces UI Framework, SQL Server).

Development of an inspection system for insurers (C#, ASP.NET, Oracle).

→ 2015 - 2015

Software Analyst

Instituto de Protección y Sanidad Agropecuaria. - Managua, NIC

Analysis, design and development of Web application. (PHP Laravel, PostgreSQL)

Adequacy of the budget system.

Adjustments of the control modules of merchandise and petty cash.(PHP Laravel, PostgreSQL)

Aptitudes

PROGRAMMING:

- Visual C#
- Java
- PHP
- VB.NET
- JavaScript
- Transact SQL

PERSISTENCE:

- MSSQL Server
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Oracle

WEB UI:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- jQuery
- Angular 2+
- Bootstrap

MIDDLE-TIER MVC FRAMEWORKS:

- .NET Framework
- .NET Core
- ASP.NET / ASP.NET Core
- LINQ
- JEE
- Entity Framework

OTHER TOOLS:

- DevExpress
- Maven
- GIT
- Azure DevOps

Education

 \rightarrow 2010 – 2015

Computing Engineer

National Engineering University - Managua, NIC

Other courses - certifications

→ 2014

Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2

Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 Implementation Course - Managua, NIC

→ 2020

MCSA: Web Applications

Microsoft - Managua, NIC

→ 2020

Scrum Fundamentals Certified

SCRUM Study - Managua, NIC